Robert Báez

Software Engineer

Santo Domingo, Rep. Dom.(GMT-4) (809) 259-4121 robertbaez1407@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/robert-baez

System Engineer with 5+ years of experience in the IT area, with technologies such as Java, Oracle, JPA, JSF, Hibernate and Spring Boot. Holding positions in the development area for companies focused on payment methods, oil refineries, and the Dominican stock market. Using tools like SQL Developer, Intellij IDEA, Eclipse, Postman, Jboss, Git, and Jenkins. I seek to continue to expand my knowledge and work with a team that allows me to grow within it.

EXPERIENCE

Cevaldom, Development engineer — August, 2021 - Nov 2024

- Improved the registration of funds massively in the system to improve more than 90%.
- Implementation of improvements and corrections for the loan module allowing performance in the process of 80%.

Tech Stack: Java 8, JEE, JPA, JSF, CSS, Oracle, SQL, Primefaces, XHTML, Git, Scrum, Postman, JSON, Maven, Jenkins, JBOSS, WILDFLY

Ministerio de Hacienda - Analyst Developer — April, 2021 - August 2021

- I worked implementing solutions and improvements for a shopping cart project focused on government services, facilitating service performance of 70%.
- Documented the cases to have better legibility of the information.

Tech Stack: Java 11, JEE, JPA, Oracle, javaScript, WildFly 23, Ubuntu, JasperReport, Postman.

Refinería, Java Developer— November, 2020 - April, 2021

- I collaborated in the development of a system for the control of input and output of materials, improving a workflow by 50%.
- I developed a project management system for the company, this allows for better organization and a reduction of time from 60% to 80%.

Tech Stack: Java 8 SE, Postgresql, Git, JPA, Netbeans.

Tecnocom, Software Developer — May, 2015 - July, 2020

- Developed requirements for different solutions focused on debit and credit cards, delinquency calculation project, reports for bank superintendence.
- Analyzed several processes in order to reduce time and improve delivery response for customers, this would improve performance in a time reduction of 40 min in the execution of processes.
- Monitored and provided support for the resolution of customer problems and cases that are worked on as a team.
- I analyzed the incidents of the clients and part of the requirements to distribute it in the team in order to conclude the tasks and incidents.
- Documented the processes carried out and generated documentation of unit tests of the developments carried out.

Tech Stack: COBOL, Java 7, ORACLE, JSP, J2EE,, SVN, Eclipse, SOAP, Shell Script, Putty.

PROJECTS

Project for barbershops — Present

• Keep track of customers who need barber services to save waiting time in shifts, for the development of this project Mongodb, NodeJs, Git, Github are used.

Material input and output system - Refinería - April, 2021

• The main objective of the project was to identify the office materials that entered and left the company, using Java 8 SE, JPA, Postgresql, Git and Netbeans.

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Intermediate: |ava, COBOL, |SF; Basic: C#, Shell Script, |avaScript.

Frameworks and Tools: Advanced: JPA; Intermediate: Scrum, Hibernate, Maven, Intellij IDEA, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Spring Boot; Basic: Angular,

Data Base: Intermediate: Oracle; Basic: Mysql, Mongo, Postgresql, SqlServer

Agile: Scrum, Agile.

Languages: Intermediate: English; Native: Spanish.

EDUCATION

Universidad Dominico Americano – República Dominicana, Santo Domingo, System *Engineering, Oct 2021.* **ITLA** – República Dominicana, Santo Domingo, Software Technologist, August *2015.*

CERTIFICATIONS

Test Java applications with JUnit 5, Mockito, Testcontainers - Udemy. 2023. Microservices: Clean Architecture, DDD, SAGA, Outbox & Kafka - Udemy. 2022.

Spring Framework 5 + REST de cero a experto – Udemy. 2022.

Docker Mastery: with kubernetes + Swarm from a Docker Captain – Udemy. 2021.

C# intermediate: Classes Interfaces and OOP – Udemy. 2020.

REFERENCES

Luis Suárez - Director TI Cevaldom 809-921-4563
Harold Gómez - Desarrollador .Net Afp Crecer 809-371-2717